<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://esteemed.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://esteemed.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-26T18:53:24+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Collaborative Staffing to grow your Business - Esteemed</title><subtitle>Scale your business with speed and confidence with trusted colleagues from the Esteemed Talent Network. Made up of over 13,000 digital professionals. The first and only integrated staffing and collaboration solution delivered through your existing communications platforms.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How Your Business Can Benefit from Remote Hiring</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/11/how-your-business-can-benefit-from-remote-hiring/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Your Business Can Benefit from Remote Hiring" /><published>2020-08-11T14:19:33+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-11T14:19:33+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/11/how-your-business-can-benefit-from-remote-hiring</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/11/how-your-business-can-benefit-from-remote-hiring/">&lt;p&gt;As many businesses face hard choices about &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rethinking the way they work&lt;/a&gt;, the world has shifted dramatically. Coronavirus will make its mark on the future of hiring too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over half of Americans have worked from home this year and many aren’t going back to the office any time soon. Most don’t want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When the pandemic is over, one in six workers is projected to continue working from home or co-working at least two days a week, according to a recent survey by economists at Harvard Business School.”—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/08/just-small-shift-remote-work-could-change-everything/614980/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to office space costs, new employee distancing regulations, masks, and cramped spaces concern many brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional office and set hours aren’t ideal for most employees. Especially while commuting and public health are major societal concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile workforces are the new normal for big tech companies like Google, Twitter, Microsoft, and Facebook. And here’s why…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-inevitable-rise-of-remote-talent&quot;&gt;The Inevitable Rise of Remote Talent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leveraging distributed teams makes perfect sense right now. This surge in “telepresence” is helping businesses to &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/can-hiring-remote-developers-save-my-agency-money/&quot; title=&quot;Learn how to save while hiring remotely.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;do way more with less&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The percentage of workers who say their employer is offering them flex time or remote work options has grown from 39% to 57% in the latest polling, conducted March 30-April 2, 2020.”—&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.gallup.com/poll/306695/workers-discovering-affinity-remote-work.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gallup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But every business owner knows the true pain points of finding the right hire. The costs of recruitment efforts alone are staggering, averaging &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2019/05/recruiting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$4000 per job in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wasted time that could be spent on important projects. The slog of recruiting the best candidates for the job from untrusted talent pools and platforms. The endless assessments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEOs still report that their biggest concern is hiring talent. Many also report that they think the current drought of talent and skill is the biggest threat to their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-your-approach-to-hiring-outdated&quot;&gt;Is Your Approach to Hiring Outdated?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the results don’t add up. Good hires seem to be a crapshoot, and your competitors are always trying to steal your best people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, when you build a distributed team to scale your business, you have access to a global talent pool. The diversity alone improves both culture and retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s why so many successful businesses have updated both their hiring and telework policies. Prospects now consider remote work a big factor in choosing an employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top talent gets snatched up fast with perks like time, location, and lifestyle flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are your recruiting methods causing you to miss out on a highly talented pool of digital employees?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-global-talent-at-your-fingertips&quot;&gt;Top Global Talent at Your Fingertips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By removing the hurdles of traditional hiring, it’s now simple to access digital superstars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the adoption of platforms like Zoom, Slack, and Google Meet, your business can quickly adapt to the new normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote hiring has cracked open the field of freelancing, and finding top talent is no longer difficult. Passionate problem-solvers are just a few clicks away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By shifting to hiring remotely, businesses can embrace the future of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remote-hiring-doesnt-have-to-be-hard&quot;&gt;Remote Hiring Doesn’t Have to Be Hard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From screenings to interviews, code assessments to culture fits, savvy businesses are making the most of this sea change in hiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, talent seems to be scattered far and wide across dozens of hiring platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we know the frustration of staffing and have made it our goal to remove the guesswork. For over a decade, we’ve networked the top talent across an incredible array of disciplines … all remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employers can easily browse hundreds of our talent profiles for digital professionals we’ve personally vetted. You can make a request and be working with trusted pros almost instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we’ve integrated every step of the process into one simple Slack channel. Gone are the days of spending an industry average &lt;strong&gt;42 days finding a fit&lt;/strong&gt;, or breaking your back for poor results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esteemed teams are known to work smarter. We’re some of the brightest digital minds in the business, and we’re all about colleagues recommending colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us do the hard part so you can get back to business as usual. &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/pricing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drop us a line today&lt;/a&gt; about all your staffing needs!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelton Reid</name></author><category term="remote work" /><category term="business" /><summary type="html">As many businesses face hard choices about rethinking the way they work, the world has shifted dramatically. Coronavirus will make its mark on the future of hiring too.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/austin-distel-guij0yszpig-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/austin-distel-guij0yszpig-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Are Happier Employees More Productive?</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/05/happy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are Happier Employees More Productive?" /><published>2020-08-05T23:52:25+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-05T23:52:25+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/05/happy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/05/happy/">&lt;p&gt;A major challenge of digital staffing is helping employees thrive. As we face changes in how we do business, who we hire, and how we hire, are paramount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work-life balance is important in a time when the world seems unstable. Skilled employees seek creative ways to get work done, both in and out of the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can your business accommodate this new work-life balance and stay on task?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-work-life-balance&quot;&gt;What Is Work-Life Balance?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balancing work, personal time, and family life is different for everyone. With some flexibility, it’s possible to create &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/&quot; title=&quot;Learn more about work-life balance. &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;solutions for workers and employers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“As we look ahead, it is clear that in order to remain competitive, employers must find ways to offer flexible work options if they want to attract and retain top talent,” said Hank Jackson, president and CEO of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shrm.org/&quot; title=&quot;Visit the Society for Human Resource Management.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Society for Human Resource Management&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For over a decade, we’ve worked with thousands of digital experts, and we know how hard it is to find the right people. For those hard-to-staff niches — like WordPress and Drupal — retention is even harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Gen Xers and Millenials list telework as a job requirement. For Gen Xers, work-life benefits include remote work and ample vacation time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In five years, Millennials will make up 75% of the workforce. They’re not as frivolous as you think. They see careers as a method for supporting their lifestyle. The office ping-pong table is a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;employee-happiness-statistics&quot;&gt;Employee Happiness Statistics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of work lies in talented, distributed networks of eager problem-solvers. And when asked about how working remotely makes them feel, the results are in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a survey from the State of Remote Work 2019 “83% of survey respondents agreed that the ability to work remotely would make them happier.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-time remote workers resoundingly replied that they were 22% happier in their jobs than those who had never worked remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a report by PGI, 82% of distributed workers reported that telecommuting reduced their stress, and 80% reported that it improved their morale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That boost in morale can make a huge difference to your bottom-line and your peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;happier-employees-are-more-creative&quot;&gt;Happier Employees Are More Creative&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses who rely on distributed workforces see the benefits. Employees work from environments best suited to their tastes or moods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greater comfort boosts creativity and can lead to innovation. For many at the top of their fields, innovation brings greater job satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And 1,100 US-based firms reported improved relations between managers and workers after going remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-impact-of-employee-happiness-on-productivity&quot;&gt;The Impact of Employee Happiness on Productivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Research has shown that employees tend to be happier with flexible work environments. As an added bonus for employers, happier employees tend to be more productive, loyal, and have higher retention rates.”—TotalWellness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI recruiters and algorithms still can’t find employees who will thrive in your business. The ghosts in the machine can only see so much about a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen other professionals struggle with finding hires, evaluating their core strengths, and endless reviews with unqualified candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand first-hand the challenges of finding the right talent for the job. But how often has a trusted colleague recommended a great hire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-the-guesswork-out-of-finding-top-talent&quot;&gt;Take the Guesswork Out of Finding Top Talent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/company/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Esteemed Talent Network&lt;/a&gt; came about from our understanding that truly productive teams are built by word-of-mouth. Colleagues referring colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With access to over 13,000 digital experts and a decade of networking, we see it over and over. And that’s why we’ve put our expertise into a solution that takes the guesswork out of staffing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let our Team Leads do the recruiting, sourcing, and code assessments for you so that you can sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want your business to be as productive as possible. So let us do the heavy lifting and find you top global talent all in one easy-to-use Slack channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assembling teams of passionate problem-solvers is our job. Yours is to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelton Reid</name></author><category term="remote hiring" /><summary type="html">A major challenge of digital staffing is helping employees thrive. As we face changes in how we do business, who we hire, and how we hire, are paramount.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/michael-dam-mez3pofgs_k-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/michael-dam-mez3pofgs_k-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Tips to Find a Web Developer for Your Business</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/5-tips-to-find-a-web-developer-for-your-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Tips to Find a Web Developer for Your Business" /><published>2020-08-04T18:54:17+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T18:54:17+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/5-tips-to-find-a-web-developer-for-your-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/5-tips-to-find-a-web-developer-for-your-business/">&lt;p&gt;Finding a web developer for your company or agency is difficult. As he or she guides the direction of your project, it is important to find a perfect fit. A strong web developer determines the success of your product. However, searching for that perfect developer is exhausting. It costs your business time and money. We understand how challenging  digital staffing can be. To get the best results for you or your team, follow our guide to hiring a web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;establish-your-budget&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish Your Budget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your scope will help determine your web resource needs. For a small month-to-month project, you might just need a part-time support developer. A larger project, for example, might require the creation of specific web or cloud-based infrastructure. Your budget will determine which web skills and services you can afford. Figuring out this step is crucial. Not certain? Esteemed can lend a hand as you’re learning your needs. The right hire will stay on track with your goals and within budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;determine-your-services&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Determine Your Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending upon your scope, you may want more than a web developer to finish the job. Web developers provide many services, but they specialize in niches. Whether they offer a full-range of services hinges on a few things: Are they a freelancer? Are they a contractor? Part of an agency? Here are some roles and responsibilities of some web-related positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;web-developers&quot;&gt;Web Developers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web developers build the functionality and features of websites. Front-end web developers focus on client-side development. Back-end developers focus on server-side development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;web-designer&quot;&gt;Web Designer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web designers focus on the look and feel of a website. They rarely program new functions or develop modules for your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;web-teams&quot;&gt;Web Teams&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web teams have developers and designers to fulfill your business’ website goals. Having a web team can ensure quality and efficiency for your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;search-for-your-talent&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search for Your Talent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find developers on practice-specific websites. These sites allow filtering and searching based on certain skills. Some will have portfolios for the developers you are searching for. This is a great place to look for any niche skills. Use a job posting site specifically for developers. Why? It ensures you’ll find a developer with the necessary skills for your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wp-contractors&quot;&gt;WP Contractors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.wpcontractors.com&quot; title=&quot;Visit WordPress Contractors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WP Contractors&lt;/a&gt; is perfect for businesses looking for WordPress developers with and without niches. They have job postings as well as different size plans that can help you find the web experts you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;upwork&quot;&gt;UpWork&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a one-off project like image editing or a quick blog, UpWork is a great platform for satisfying an immediate need. However, you will have to sift through hundreds of profiles in order to accomplish your goals, costing you time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;drupal-contractors&quot;&gt;Drupal Contractors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big site? Use Drupal? &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.drupalcontractors.com&quot; title=&quot;Visit Drupal Contractors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drupal Contractors&lt;/a&gt; is for web developers that have years of Drupal experience. Browse through their portfolios and skills to find the right Drupal web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;linkedin&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for web developers on LinkedIn can be strenuous. As you’re scouting talent, you’ll find developers from around the globe with a variety of different backgrounds. On LinkedIn, be certain you have a vetting process in place to help pre-screen your talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;esteemed&quot;&gt;Esteemed&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we’ve pre-screened our 13,000+ resources in areas like WordPress, Drupal, E-commerce, and UI/UX. Our unique team of &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce/&quot; title=&quot;Learn more about a distributed workforce. &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;distributed&lt;/a&gt;, digital experts integrate with your company’s communication networks. Instantly, you are connected with resource managers who will help you get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/&quot; title=&quot;Learn more about our Talent Network!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;talent you need&lt;/a&gt; to finish your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-to-work&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get to Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve chosen your talent, it’s time to start the project. Only working with a web developer? If you don’t have a project manager, you must communicate anticipated due dates and project milestones. Remember this is your project. Trust your developer’s expertise, and let them guide you. Nitpicking can  slow down your project. Additionally, make sure to review progress when it is provided. Developers can’t move on with your project until then. If you delay your feedback, you run the risk of delaying your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pay-your-developer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay Your Developer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handling contracts without a dedicated hiring resource? Make sure to read the terms of your developer’s contract. Agree on milestones, and continue to provide payment as the project progresses. Set expectations, but be flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring a web developer is not always easy, but that doesn’t mean it has to be a bad experience. Hopefully you’ll learn more about your project as you learn more about what different developers are capable of. You’ll also have more time to focus on the things that matter to you, like scaling your business. Once you have a good relationship with the right candidate, they’ll ideally become your client for life! Need help finding that trusted advisor? &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/sales/schedule-demo/&quot; title=&quot;Schedule a Demo!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Talk with us today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gloria Tucker</name></author><category term="web development" /><category term="remote work" /><category term="talent network" /><summary type="html">Finding a web developer for your company or agency is difficult. As he or she guides the direction of your project, it is important to find a perfect fit. A strong web developer determines the success of your product. However, searching for that perfect developer is exhausting. It costs your business time and money. We understand how challenging digital staffing can be. To get the best results for you or your team, follow our guide to hiring a web developer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/kelly-sikkema-yk0hpwwdj1i-unsplash-1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/kelly-sikkema-yk0hpwwdj1i-unsplash-1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Can Hiring Remote Developers Save My Agency Money?</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/can-hiring-remote-developers-save-my-agency-money/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can Hiring Remote Developers Save My Agency Money?" /><published>2020-08-04T01:53:08+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T01:53:08+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/can-hiring-remote-developers-save-my-agency-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/can-hiring-remote-developers-save-my-agency-money/">&lt;p&gt;Your business or agency may be making a critical decision to hire remote employees to help you grow. But many talented web developers and engineers have a backlog of clients. Just getting in contact with them can be a full-time job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce/&quot; title=&quot;Learn more about a distributed team.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Working with a distributed team&lt;/a&gt; may seem daunting, but many companies are already fully remote. We’re seeing the future of work change right before our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, can employing distributed, remote web developers actually save you money? The short answer? Yes. And it will save you more than just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;save-yourself-the-headache&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save Yourself the Headache&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is money. Banging your head against a wall is not how you should be spending it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand the frustration of &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/03/should-i-consider-contract-staffing/&quot; title=&quot;Learn more about contract staffing. &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;digital staffing&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve made it our goal to remove the guesswork and pain points along the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demand for top-tier developers has never been higher, and we don’t want all the great talent out there to go to waste!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand that the best hires are scattered far and wide. That’s why we founded &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/sales/schedule-demo/&quot; title=&quot;Schedule a demo!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Esteemed&lt;/a&gt;, our curated network of top-performing hires, all in one easy-to-access Slack channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For over a decade we’ve made it our mission to help businesses and agencies seamlessly harness the power of passionate problem-solvers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we’ve seen some pretty staggering results in the way business gets done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-remote-web-developers-consider-remote-a-benefit&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Remote Web Developers Consider Remote a Benefit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve discussed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;effects remote work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;has on employee productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that remote teams work longer hours and are more willing to put in overtime than on-site employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job flexibility is something that most top recruits look for today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global firms and agencies too have reported more positive relationships between managers and remote developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“95% of employers say that telework has a high impact on employee retention.”— PGI.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see it every day on the happy faces of our clients and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Esteemed Talent Network&lt;/a&gt;. That’s good business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bottom-line-for-your-business-or-agency&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bottom-Line for Your Business or Agency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the real bottom-line for your business? Output and efficiency are important factors in your success. That balance is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“… A typical employer can save an average of $11,000 per half-time telecommuter per year. The primary savings are the result of increased productivity, lower real estate costs, reduced absenteeism and turnover, and better disaster preparedness.” —&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalworkplaceanalytics.com/telecommuting-statistics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Global Workplace Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimizing that path forward is an important step on the journey. By investing more in your talent, you actually save more. We can’t ignore the evidence. Save money and sanity by staffing smarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;let-us-do-the-heavy-lifting&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let Us Do the Heavy Lifting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been there. We know the impact years of networking with 13,000+ of the best digital professionals makes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we developed a frictionless solution to harness those resources. Now you don’t have to sweat the petty stuff. Leave us to do the recruiting and vetting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find instant access to hundreds of pre-screened digital professionals in those tricky-to-staff niches like &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.wpcontractors.com&quot; title=&quot;Visit WordPress Contractors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.drupalcontractors.com&quot; title=&quot;Visit Drupal Contractors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt;, React, E-commerce, and more coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means you can relax, and get straight to work making a difference out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to chatting! &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/sales/schedule-demo/&quot; title=&quot;Let's chat! &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drop us a line &lt;/a&gt;any time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelton Reid</name></author><category term="remote work" /><category term="agencies" /><category term="business" /><summary type="html">Your business or agency may be making a critical decision to hire remote employees to help you grow. But many talented web developers and engineers have a backlog of clients. Just getting in contact with them can be a full-time job.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/micheile-henderson-zvprbbmt8qa-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/micheile-henderson-zvprbbmt8qa-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Should I Consider Contract Staffing?</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/03/should-i-consider-contract-staffing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Should I Consider Contract Staffing?" /><published>2020-08-03T18:28:56+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T18:28:56+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/03/should-i-consider-contract-staffing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/03/should-i-consider-contract-staffing/">&lt;p&gt;Times have changed. Even before Covid-19 disrupted workplace behavior, the labor market was transforming. Now, this evolution is in overdrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metlife.com/content/dam/metlifecom/us/ebts/pdf/MetLife_EBTS-GigReport_2019.pdf&quot; title=&quot;MetLife Gig Report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;One in four American workers&lt;/a&gt; use freelancing/independent contracting as either their primary or supplemental source of income, according to a MetLife report. “It’s not just a trend,” the study finds, “it’s a fundamental shift in how our economy operates.” Even if your company bears all the hallmarks of a traditional workforce, you’re no longer immune to the “gig economy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a traditional employer, your talent pool might be shifting their gaze. If you’re already using contractors, you’re likely facing challenges with finding highly-qualified talent.  As more and more digital experts seek contract employment, it’s grown increasingly time-consuming to find the right person for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-contract-staffing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Contract Staffing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a full-time hire doesn’t fit a position, contract staffing is an alternative. Contract staffing presents companies with talented people that specialize in a given role or industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your organization experiencing rapid expansion? Do you need additional resources for upcoming projects or roles? Contract staffing connects you with candidates for a specific task or time-frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contract staffing suits companies experiencing rapid growth. It’s also an invaluable tool for stable businesses that want top talent at the right price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-benefits-of-contract-staffing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Are the Benefits of Contract Staffing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional staffing is expensive. It’s also tedious, lengthy, and offers no guarantee that you’ll find the right person for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need time to source resumes, recruit in-demand talent, screen for necessary skill sets, and lump in recurring expenses—it all adds up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-perfectly-tailored-fit&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Perfectly-Tailored Fit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contract staffing addresses the pain points of job recruitment, giving you flexibility and scalability. Contractors are the solution to elastic workforces, workloads, and workplaces. When you find yourself short-staffed, you can hire someone with role-specific attributes. When projects end or seasonal efforts dry up, you won’t be stuck with employees who have nothing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are ample problems that stem from having too many or too few employees. Avoid these issues by strengthening your core team with contractors and freelancers. A successful company manages fluctuations and handles change in stride. In our modern world, the workforce is fluid and digitally-savvy. You should be, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;reduction-in-hiring-costs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduction in Hiring Costs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the hiring process for contract staffing takes less time, you save big. Recruitment costs less for contractors than full-time employees, too. By &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/&quot; title=&quot;Partner with us! &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;partnering with a contract staffing agency&lt;/a&gt;, you skip lengthy interviewing and vetting processes with busy decision-makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You pay your contractors only for the hours they work or jobs they complete, as opposed to salaried positions with benefits. Recurring expenses like healthcare, 401(k) contributions and PTO won’t apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-should-i-turn-for-contract-staffing-solutions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Should I Turn for Contract Staffing Solutions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no centralized source for contractors and freelancers. Talent is scattered. Developers and engineers are on LinkedIn, Indeed, job boards, and working for your competitors. Your touchpoints are overwhelming. Looking for &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/&quot; title=&quot;Learn more about our Talent Network.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;top talent&lt;/a&gt; in a sea of choices is no easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to fill a technical position? Work with an industry-specific contract staffing agency, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.wpcontractors.com&quot; title=&quot;Visit WPContractors!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WP Contractors&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.drupalcontractors.com&quot; title=&quot;Visit DrupalContractors!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drupal Contractors&lt;/a&gt;. It’s better than trying to recruit a developer contractor on your own. Why? Tech staffing differs from other freelance and contractor placement. There’s a fundamental lack of engineers and technical management, making it hard to find your ideal candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-should-i-look-for-in-a-contract-staffing-agency&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Should I Look for in a Contract Staffing Agency?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for a reliable pipeline of qualified professionals? Your best bet is a contract staffing agency. Not all agencies are created equal, however. Here are some questions to ask as you search for the right partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-your-contractors-pre-screened&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are Your Contractors Pre-Screened?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can anyone with internet access and a resume apply, or is there a more rigorous screening process? The stricter the application procedures, the less work you have to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-area-of-expertise&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Is Your Area of Expertise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many agencies choose to focus their efforts on certain industries or roles. You want an agency that can navigate job-specific challenges and requirements. If you find a trusted partner that you work well with, they can likely assist you in other areas. Try to develop a working relationship so that when you have jobs to fill, your agency knows exactly who you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-the-hiring-process-like&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the Hiring Process Like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you need help, how quickly can you receive it? Does a fast turnaround time affect the quality of your hire? How many steps must you go through before you see results?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;will-i-need-to-integrate-a-new-tool-or-platform&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will I Need to Integrate a New Tool or Platform?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If transparency and communication are important to your hiring process, how will your agency contribute to your company goals? Will you be asked to learn new tools? Does this agency work with your existing platforms? At Esteemed, for example, we offer a reliable pipeline of pre-screened individuals that you can tap into from Slack. All you need to do is make requests in your private channel. We’ll connect you with top talent almost instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staffing your organization with contractors and freelancers is cost-effective and well-suited for the modern workplace. Considering the trends in remote work and contract positions, you’re at a competitive disadvantage if you don’t capitalize on this hiring strategy. You can find the best talent at reasonable prices. Best of all, you don’t have to break a sweat if you team up with the right agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn more? &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/sales/schedule-demo/&quot; title=&quot;Get in touch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get in touch with us today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Casey Horgan</name></author><category term="talent network" /><category term="remote work" /><category term="contract staffing" /><summary type="html">Times have changed. Even before Covid-19 disrupted workplace behavior, the labor market was transforming. Now, this evolution is in overdrive.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/pexels-burst-374085.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/pexels-burst-374085.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Can Remote Work Increase Employee Productivity?</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can Remote Work Increase Employee Productivity?" /><published>2020-08-01T14:47:36+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-01T14:47:36+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;Our new normal has many businesses and contractors rethinking the future of work. Throughout the current economic uncertainty and global pandemic, remote work is on everyone’s mind. But should you embrace it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, allowing remote work for your teams and contractors might feel unsettling. But chances are your remote employees will thank you for trusting them to find their ideal working environment. Your business or brand might even see some big results by allowing #remotework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-boost-employee-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Boost Employee Productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we’re on a mission to help people around the world work smarter, not harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For nearly a decade, we’ve been tracking how remote work positively impacts our network. Our colleagues and clients see the difference too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“65% of employees believe they’re more productive when they work outside of the office, and 47% wish their company provided this benefit.”—&lt;a href=&quot;https://clockify.me/blog/productivity/increase-employee-productivity/&quot; title=&quot;Marja Kojic's Biography&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marija Kojic&lt;/a&gt;, Productivity Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the whole, remote teams get more done. And they do it all without a dreadful commute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-does-remote-work-help-skyrocket-performance&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Does Remote Work Help Skyrocket Performance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WFA (Work from Anywhere) is the new WFH (Work from Home). Workplace elasticity lets you be your own boss, keep flexible hours, and focus on the tasks that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most top-tier developers have avoided the traditional office for years. 44% of remote employees said they were less distracted when they worked from home. No more endless meetings, office distractions, or annoying coworkers. The bedroom is the new boardroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;employee-productivity-vs-hours-worked&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employee Productivity Vs. Hours Worked&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One misconception about distributed teams is that they work fewer hours than their on-site counterparts. This is simply not true. Remote workers say they work more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owllabs.com/state-of-remote-work/2019&quot; title=&quot;Remote Work Report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;40 hours per week&lt;/a&gt;, 43% more than on-site workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The State of Remote Work Survey discovered the biggest reasons employees choose remote work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better work-life balance (91%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased productivity/better focus (79%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less stress (78%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoiding a commute (78%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A distributed workforce can elevate a company’s efficiency, as well as boost employee morale and customer satisfaction. With flexible schedules, remote teams no longer need to worry about the yoke of the 9-to-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remote-work-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote Work Productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results are in. If brands want to get to the next level, they need to embrace remote work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we rub elbows with diverse, global digital rockstars every day. We see the benefits of WFA and distributed teams first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies have shown how much more productive, engaged, and effective employees can be when they’re empowered to choose where, when, and how they’ll get work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-you-really-measure-employee-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can You Really Measure Employee Productivity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity metrics and benchmarks will be different for every business. Your productive output and efficiency are important factors to your success, and that balance is delicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimizing that path forward is an important step on the journey, and that’s why we can’t ignore the evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“… A typical employer can save an average of $11,000 per half-time telecommuter per year. The primary savings are the result of increased productivity, lower real estate costs, reduced absenteeism and turnover, and better disaster preparedness.” —&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalworkplaceanalytics.com/telecommuting-statistics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Global Workplace Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than math, we’ve seen the difference in output first-hand, and the future is bright!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in need of an extra pair of trusted hands, a technical expert, or a strategic advisor with one of your projects, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re 13,000+ strong and growing, distributed, and experienced in all things digital.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelton Reid</name></author><category term="remote work" /><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">Our new normal has many businesses and contractors rethinking the future of work. Throughout the current economic uncertainty and global pandemic, remote work is on everyone’s mind. But should you embrace it?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/pexels-cottonbro-4064821.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/pexels-cottonbro-4064821.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Reasons Why You Should Join a Talent Network</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Reasons Why You Should Join a Talent Network" /><published>2020-07-25T14:25:03+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-25T14:25:03+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/">&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we have spent a decade building our Talent Network. Having started an agency in 2011, we have sponsored countless events, amassed an impressive list of clients and formed many relationships with top talent. We’re a community of pre-screened digital professionals spread across multiple disciplines and categories. We have practices focused on CMS (WordPress, Drupal, Sitecore, AEM and more), E-commerce, UX, and Cloud. We deliver our service via the tools our clients already use. Built on Slack, our premier platform allows us to post open roles, communicate, and collaborate with client employers and client providers. We can connect you with a potential hiring manager in minutes. A network of this type removes the burden of business development from a contractor and provides a &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/03/should-i-consider-contract-staffing/&quot; title=&quot;Learn more about the benefits of the contract workforce.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;host of other benefits&lt;/a&gt; even for those seeking full-time work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;less-time-searching-more-time-working&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less Time Searching, More Time Working&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job search process can be long and drawn-out with many interviews, conversations, and redundant screening. Even if you do find a great opportunity, you might repeat the same search process a few months later once your project wraps up. At Esteemed we vouch for you with our clients. To do that we screen and qualify your experience, offer feedback that we think will help, and connect you with new opportunities that will be a fit as they come through our pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we’re on Slack, our jobs are posted directly in their respective channels. Looking for new opportunities in Magento, or another related field? Fill out your profile, get in touch, and join the channel for your discipline (#magento, #drupal). Less time searching for jobs means more time focusing on learning new skills or having fun. That’s what we are all about, making work more flexible, abundant and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stand-out-from-the-crowd&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out from the Crowd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our years in the digital space we find companies work with who they trust. When you join our talent network, you’re pre-qualifying yourself for open roles listed with Esteemed. Just by signing up and going through our vetting process you are verifying your skills to one of our leads. Our clients have come to trust these individuals as if they were their own staff. We try to keep the process as minimal as possible, yet a thorough review of everyone in the network is needed to make strong recommendations. From there you have access to mentorship, support, and collaboration with 500 peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grow-your-own-network&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grow Your Own Network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you join the Esteemed Talent Network, you gain access to hundreds on Slack and thousands in the network at large. &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/5-tips-to-find-a-web-developer-for-your-business/&quot; title=&quot;Learn how to hire a web developer.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Developers&lt;/a&gt;, architects, project managers and other digital professionals with a range of experience are available for questions, collaboration or even teaming up on a project that you might need help with. Got a quick question about &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.drupalcontractors.com/blogs/come-commerce-drupal-way&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drupal Commerce&lt;/a&gt;? Reach out to one of our Drupal experts on our #drupal Slack channel and start a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Esteemed members are always happy to offer advice, insight, and support. We’re a friendly, open company and we pride ourselves on our ability to build relationships with quality talent and grow lasting connections—whether that be between employer clients or members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;join-our-inside-track&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Our Inside Track&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, you can also gain access to opportunities not listed on job sites. More than half of job seekers report that their preferred source for finding jobs is online. The second most popular method? Hearing about jobs from a friend or trusted colleague. We keep a close eye on our current and potential clients, and often hear about their needs first. This means they come to us first before posting on LinkedIn, Indeed, or even on their own website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of our unique relationship with agencies and organizations, joining our talent network might even assist with transforming your skill-set to a new area. For example: a developer who may want to transition to Project Management, or an Executive role. We have helped many in the network transition to related areas. We believe in doing what you love. For some, that can change over time. We are here to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-little-help-from-your-friends&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Little Help from Your Friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer people can feel lonely, and lack a support system found in traditional settings. Even if you are on contract at a big company, you are still “a contractor.” Being part of Esteemed provides a large and diverse support system. Whether you are looking for a simple coding solution or a few extra hands, we’re here to help! We know that team camaraderie encourages confidence, increases access to knowledge, and invites shared experiences. We believe being part of a talent network means not only helping you get gigs, but helping scale and grow your skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;become-a-partner&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Become a Partner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, although not one of our five reasons to join, we find relationships are everything in the workplace. Our Internal Partners Program provides developers and small agencies of five or less with the resources they need at insider pricing. If you’re a sole developer or an agency who doesn’t want to turn down that big project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/partners/partner-registration/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;let’s talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our talent network is a place to explore opportunities, share ideas, meet new colleagues and join interesting projects. As we bring members from around the world together for collaboration, work, and networking we are committed to help contractors grow their business and those seeking full-time work find the employer of their dreams. Want to learn more? &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/company/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Come join us!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Matthew Pritchard</name></author><category term="talent network" /><category term="remote work" /><summary type="html">At Esteemed, we have spent a decade building our Talent Network. Having started an agency in 2011, we have sponsored countless events, amassed an impressive list of clients and formed many relationships with top talent. We’re a community of pre-screened digital professionals spread across multiple disciplines and categories. We have practices focused on CMS (WordPress, Drupal, Sitecore, AEM and more), E-commerce, UX, and Cloud. We deliver our service via the tools our clients already use. Built on Slack, our premier platform allows us to post open roles, communicate, and collaborate with client employers and client providers. We can connect you with a potential hiring manager in minutes. A network of this type removes the burden of business development from a contractor and provides a host of other benefits even for those seeking full-time work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/talentnetwork-1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/talentnetwork-1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Benefits of a Distributed Workforce</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Benefits of a Distributed Workforce" /><published>2020-07-08T10:56:15+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T10:56:15+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce/">&lt;p&gt;Whether we want to admit it or not, everything has changed. The future of work, in light of the “new normal,” presents some very unique challenges and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s never been a greater opportunity for disruption, but this also means more chances for failure. By being flexible, agile, and empathetic, we all have the best chance to create change, make a difference, and succeed in this new world of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we believe that &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the future of work&lt;/a&gt; lies with highly-talented, diverse, and well-trusted teams of distributed workers. Both employers and employees are seizing the opportunities offered by this emerging revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future-will-be-evenly-distributed&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future Will Be (Evenly) Distributed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/smart-office/how-a-distributed-workforce-makes-employees-work-smarter-a46febf3cb35&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;distributed workforce&lt;/a&gt; refers to personnel geographically distributed over large areas who make the best use of advanced technology to go beyond the limitations of the traditional working model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter recently announced moving up its timeline to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;keep much of its workforce remote&lt;/a&gt; when they realized the benefits. Not only were employees safer, but they were also happier and more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming advances in 5G, remote work platforms, video conferencing, VPNs, and a culture that embraces online life, all point to the benefits of a distributed workforce,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also ditching the &lt;em&gt;old ways of hiring&lt;/em&gt; — that can comprise months of wasted effort — for simple, consolidated staffing solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-benefits-of-distributed-teams&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Benefits of Distributed Teams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand the frustration of staffing and have made it our goal to remove the guesswork. For over a decade we’ve made it our business to help businesses easily harness the power of distributed workforces to find …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased employee productivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happier employees who are more productive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top global talent at your fingertips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved culture, loyalty, and retention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And a better bottom-line for your business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-increased-employee-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Increased Employee Productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employers have been surprised that &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/&quot; title=&quot;Read more on employee productivity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;productivity skyrockets when workers go remote&lt;/a&gt;, even part-time. The flexibility of telecommuting has brought an infusion of energy to the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many top-tier developers have avoided the traditional office for years for good reason. In fact, 44% of remote employees said they were less distracted when they worked from home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-happier-employees-are-more-productive&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Happier Employees Are More Productive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy workers get more done. In a survey from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owllabs.com/state-of-remote-work/2019&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;State of Remote Work 2019&lt;/a&gt; “83% of survey respondents agreed that the ability to work remotely would make them happier.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that ~1,100 US-based firms reported improved relations between managers and workers after implementing a remote-work program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-top-global-talent-at-your-fingertips&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Top Global Talent at Your Fingertips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Esteemed, you can quickly source &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/03/should-i-consider-contract-staffing/&quot; title=&quot;Find digital professionals today!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;digital professionals&lt;/a&gt; from a pre-vetted pool of global super-stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days of murky job sites, bad leads, unreliable recruiters, and wasted weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-improved-culture-loyalty-and-retention&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Improved Culture, Loyalty, and Retention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now more than ever organizations desire a diversity of voices, global leaders with unique viewpoints, and loyal employees who consider flexibility a benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a PGI think-piece, 95% of employers say that telework has a high impact on employee retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-the-bottom-line-for-your-business&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The Bottom-Line for Your Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rising costs of office equipment and space, remote employees can &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/04/can-hiring-remote-developers-save-my-agency-money/&quot; title=&quot;Learn how to save by hiring. &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;save the average business&lt;/a&gt; close to $11,000 annually for even a part-time hire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations that have never considered distributed workforces are now facing one simple fact: Adapt, or be left in the dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-revolution-will-be-distributed&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Revolution Will Be Distributed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to transform the workday?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a results-oriented developer or digital professional looking to bolster your portfolio or meet some new and amazing clients, we’d love to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re an agency or business that wants to tap into our deep talent network, &lt;a href=&quot;/pricing/&quot; title=&quot;Let's Connect!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;let’s chat&lt;/a&gt;. Save yourself time, money, and little bit of sanity in these challenging times.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Matthew Pritchard</name></author><category term="remote work" /><category term="working from home" /><summary type="html">Whether we want to admit it or not, everything has changed. The future of work, in light of the “new normal,” presents some very unique challenges and solutions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/woman-lying-and-typing-on-laptop-6249.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/woman-lying-and-typing-on-laptop-6249.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>