<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://esteemed.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://esteemed.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-03T18:36:49+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Esteemed.io</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Can Remote Work Increase Employee Productivity?</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can Remote Work Increase Employee Productivity?" /><published>2020-08-01T14:47:36+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-01T14:47:36+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;Our new normal has many businesses and contractors rethinking the future of work. Throughout the current economic uncertainty and global pandemic, remote work is on everyone’s mind. But should you embrace it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, allowing remote work for your teams and contractors might feel unsettling. But chances are your remote employees will thank you for trusting them to find their ideal working environment. Your business or brand might even see some big results by allowing #remotework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-boost-employee-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Boost Employee Productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we’re on a mission to help people around the world work smarter, not harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For nearly a decade, we’ve been tracking how remote work positively impacts our network. Our colleagues and clients see the difference too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“65% of employees believe they’re more productive when they work outside of the office, and 47% wish their company provided this benefit.”—&lt;a href=&quot;https://clockify.me/blog/productivity/increase-employee-productivity/&quot; title=&quot;Marja Kojic's Biography&quot;&gt;Marija Kojic&lt;/a&gt;, Productivity Writer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the whole, remote teams get more done. And they do it all without a dreadful commute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-does-remote-work-help-skyrocket-performance&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Does Remote Work Help Skyrocket Performance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WFA (Work from Anywhere) is the new WFH (Work from Home). Workplace elasticity lets you be your own boss, keep flexible hours, and focus on the tasks that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most top-tier developers have avoided the traditional office for years. 44% of remote employees said they were less distracted when they worked from home. No more endless meetings, office distractions, or annoying coworkers. The bedroom is the new boardroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;employee-productivity-vs-hours-worked&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employee Productivity Vs. Hours Worked&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One misconception about distributed teams is that they work fewer hours than their on-site counterparts. This is simply not true. Remote workers say they work more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owllabs.com/state-of-remote-work/2019&quot; title=&quot;Remote Work Report&quot;&gt;40 hours per week&lt;/a&gt;, 43% more than on-site workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The State of Remote Work Survey discovered the biggest reasons employees choose remote work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better work-life balance (91%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased productivity/better focus (79%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less stress (78%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoiding a commute (78%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A distributed workforce can elevate a company’s efficiency, as well as boost employee morale and customer satisfaction. With flexible schedules, remote teams no longer need to worry about the yoke of the 9-to-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;remote-work-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote Work Productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results are in. If brands want to get to the next level, they need to embrace remote work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we rub elbows with diverse, global digital rockstars every day. We see the benefits of WFA and distributed teams first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies have shown how much more productive, engaged, and effective employees can be when they’re empowered to choose where, when, and how they’ll get work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-you-really-measure-employee-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can You Really Measure Employee Productivity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity metrics and benchmarks will be different for every business. Your productive output and efficiency are important factors to your success, and that balance is delicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimizing that path forward is an important step on the journey, and that’s why we can’t ignore the evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“… A typical employer can save an average of $11,000 per half-time telecommuter per year. The primary savings are the result of increased productivity, lower real estate costs, reduced absenteeism and turnover, and better disaster preparedness.” —&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalworkplaceanalytics.com/telecommuting-statistics&quot;&gt;Global Workplace Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than math, we’ve seen the difference in output first-hand, and the future is bright!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in need of an extra pair of trusted hands, a technical expert, or a strategic advisor with one of your projects, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re 13,000+ strong and growing, distributed, and experienced in all things digital.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelton Reid</name></author><category term="remote work" /><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">Our new normal has many businesses and contractors rethinking the future of work. Throughout the current economic uncertainty and global pandemic, remote work is on everyone’s mind. But should you embrace it?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/pexels-cottonbro-4064821.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/pexels-cottonbro-4064821.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Reasons Why You Should Join a Talent Network</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Reasons Why You Should Join a Talent Network" /><published>2020-07-25T14:25:03+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-25T14:25:03+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/">&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we have spent a decade building our Talent Network. Having started an agency in 2011, we have sponsored countless events, amassed an impressive list of clients and formed many relationships with top talent. We’re a community of pre-screened digital professionals spread across multiple disciplines and categories. We have practices focused on CMS (WordPress, Drupal, Sitecore, AEM and more), E-commerce, UX, and Cloud. We deliver our service via the tools our clients already use. Built on Slack our premier platform allows us to post open roles, communicate and collaborate with client employers and client providers. We can connect you with a potential hiring manager in minutes. A network of this type removes the burden of business development from a contractor and provides a host of other benefits even for those seeking full-time work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;less-time-searching-more-time-working&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less Time Searching, More Time Working&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job search process can be long and drawn-out with many interviews, conversations, and redundant screening. Even if you do find a great opportunity, you might repeat the same search process a few months later once your project wraps up. At Esteemed we vouch for you with our clients. To do that we screen and qualify your experience, offer feedback that we think will help, and connect you with new opportunities that will be a fit as they come through our pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we’re on Slack, our jobs are posted directly in their respective channels. Looking for new opportunities in Magento, or another related field? Fill out your profile, get in touch, and join the channel for your discipline (#magento, #drupal). Less time searching for jobs means more time focusing on learning new skills or having fun. That’s what we are all about, making work more flexible, abundant and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stand-out-from-the-crowd&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out from the Crowd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our years in the digital space we find companies work with who they trust. When you join our talent network, you’re pre-qualifying yourself for open roles listed with Esteemed. Just by signing up and going through our vetting process you are verifying your skills to one of our leads. Our clients have come to trust these individuals as if they were their own staff. We try to keep the process as minimal as possible, yet a thorough review of everyone in the network is needed to make strong recommendations. From there you have access to mentorship, support, and collaboration with 500 peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grow-your-own-network&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grow Your Own Network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you join the Esteemed Talent Network, you gain access to hundreds on Slack and thousands in the network at large. Developers, architects, project managers and other digital professionals with a range of experience are available for questions, collaboration or even teaming up on a project that you might need help with. Got a quick question about &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.drupalcontractors.com/blogs/come-commerce-drupal-way&quot;&gt;Drupal Commerce&lt;/a&gt;? Reach out to one of our Drupal experts on our #drupal Slack channel and start a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Esteemed members are always happy to offer advice, insight, and support. We’re a friendly, open company and we pride ourselves on our ability to build relationships with quality talent and grow lasting connections—whether that be between employer clients or members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-our-inside-track&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Our Inside Track&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, you can also gain access to opportunities not listed on job sites. More than half of job seekers report that their preferred source for finding jobs is online. The second most popular method? Hearing about jobs from a friend or trusted colleague. We keep a close eye on our current and potential clients, and often hear about their needs first. This means they come to us first before posting on LinkedIn, Indeed, or even on their own website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of our unique relationship with agencies and organizations, joining our talent network might even assist with transforming your skill-set to a new area. For example, a developer who may want to transition to Project Management or an Executive role. We have helped many in the network transition to related areas. We believe in doing what you love. For some, that can change over time. We are here to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-help-from-your-friends&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Little Help from Your Friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer people can feel lonely, and lack a support system found in traditional settings. Even if you are on contract at a big company, you are still “a contractor.” Being part of Esteemed provides a large and diverse support system. Whether you are looking for a simple coding solution or a few extra hands, we’re here to help! We know that team camaraderie encourages confidence, increases access to knowledge, and invites shared experiences. We believe being part of a talent network means not only helping you get gigs, but helping scale and grow your skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;become-a-partner&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Become a Partner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, although not one of our five reasons to join, we find relationships are everything in the workplace. Our Internal Partners Program provides developers and small agencies of five or less with the resources they need at insider pricing. If you’re a sole developer or an agency who doesn’t want to turn down that big project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/partners/partner-registration/&quot;&gt;let’s talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our talent network is a place to explore opportunities, share ideas, meet new colleagues and join interesting projects. As we bring members from around the world together for collaboration, work, and networking we are committed to help contractors grow their business and those seeking full-time work find the employer of their dreams. Want to learn more? &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/company/&quot;&gt;Come join us!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Matthew Pritchard</name></author><category term="talent network" /><category term="remote work" /><category term="partner program" /><summary type="html">At Esteemed, we have spent a decade building our Talent Network. Having started an agency in 2011, we have sponsored countless events, amassed an impressive list of clients and formed many relationships with top talent. We’re a community of pre-screened digital professionals spread across multiple disciplines and categories. We have practices focused on CMS (WordPress, Drupal, Sitecore, AEM and more), E-commerce, UX, and Cloud. We deliver our service via the tools our clients already use. Built on Slack our premier platform allows us to post open roles, communicate and collaborate with client employers and client providers. We can connect you with a potential hiring manager in minutes. A network of this type removes the burden of business development from a contractor and provides a host of other benefits even for those seeking full-time work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/talentnetwork.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/talentnetwork.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Benefits of a Distributed Workforce</title><link href="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Benefits of a Distributed Workforce" /><published>2020-07-08T10:56:15+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T10:56:15+00:00</updated><id>https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/08/5-benefits-of-a-distributed-workforce/">&lt;p&gt;Whether we want to admit it or not, everything has changed. The future of work, in light of the “new normal,” presents some very unique challenges and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s never been a greater opportunity for disruption, but this also means more chances for failure. By being flexible, agile, and empathetic, we all have the best chance to create change, make a difference, and succeed in this new world of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Esteemed, we believe that &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/07/25/5-reasons-why-you-should-join-a-talent-network/&quot;&gt;the future of work&lt;/a&gt; lies with highly-talented, diverse, and well-trusted teams of distributed workers. Both employers and employees are seizing the opportunities offered by this emerging revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future-will-be-evenly-distributed&quot;&gt;The Future Will Be (Evenly) Distributed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/smart-office/how-a-distributed-workforce-makes-employees-work-smarter-a46febf3cb35&quot;&gt;distributed workforce&lt;/a&gt; refers to personnel geographically distributed over large areas who make the best use of advanced technology to go beyond the limitations of the traditional working model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter recently announced moving up its timeline to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever&quot;&gt;keep much of its workforce remote&lt;/a&gt; when they realized the benefits. Not only were employees safer, but they were also happier and more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming advances in 5G, remote work platforms, video conferencing, VPNs, and a culture that embraces online life, all point to the benefits of a distributed workforce,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also ditching the &lt;em&gt;old ways of hiring&lt;/em&gt; — that can comprise months of wasted effort — for simple, consolidated staffing solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-benefits-of-distributed-teams&quot;&gt;5 Benefits of Distributed Teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand the frustration of staffing and have made it our goal to remove the guesswork. For over a decade we’ve made it our business to help businesses easily harness the power of distributed workforces to find …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased employee productivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happier employees who are more productive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top global talent at your fingertips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved culture, loyalty, and retention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And a better bottom-line for your business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;increased-employee-productivity&quot;&gt;Increased Employee Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employers have been surprised that &lt;a href=&quot;https://esteemed.io/blog/2020/08/01/can-remote-work-increase-employee-productivity/&quot; title=&quot;Read more on employee productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;productivity skyrockets when workers go remote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, even part-time. The flexibility of telecommuting has brought an infusion of energy to the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many top-tier developers have avoided the traditional office for years for good reason. 44% of remote employees said they were less distracted when they worked from home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;happier-employees-are-more-productive&quot;&gt;Happier Employees Are More Productive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy workers get more done. In a survey from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owllabs.com/state-of-remote-work/2019&quot;&gt;State of Remote Work 2019&lt;/a&gt; “83% of survey respondents agreed that the ability to work remotely would make them happier.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that ~1,100 US-based firms reported improved relations between managers and workers after implementing a remote-work program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-global-talent-at-your-fingertips&quot;&gt;Top Global Talent at Your Fingertips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Esteemed, you can quickly source digital professionals from a pre-vetted pool of global super-stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days of murky job sites, bad leads, unreliable recruiters, and wasted weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improved-culture-loyalty-and-retention&quot;&gt;Improved Culture, Loyalty, and Retention&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now more than ever organizations desire a diversity of voices, global leaders with unique viewpoints, and loyal employees who consider flexibility a benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The impact of telecommuting on employee retention is among the least controversial findings—95% of employers say that telework has a high impact on employee retention.”— &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pgi.com/blog/2019/11/how-telecommuting-saves-money-and-the-planet-too/&quot;&gt;PGI.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bottom-line-for-your-business&quot;&gt;The Bottom-Line for Your Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rising costs of office equipment and space, remote employees can save the average business close to $11,000 annually for even a part-time hire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations that have never considered distributed workforces are now facing one simple fact: Adapt, or be left in the dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-revolution-will-be-distributed&quot;&gt;The Revolution Will Be Distributed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to transform the workday?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a results-oriented developer or digital professional looking to bolster your portfolio or meet some new and amazing clients, we’d love to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re an agency or business that wants to tap into our deep talent network, &lt;a href=&quot;/pricing/&quot; title=&quot;Let's Connect!&quot;&gt;let’s chat&lt;/a&gt;. Save yourself time, money, and little bit of sanity in these challenging times.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Matthew Pritchard</name></author><category term="remote work" /><category term="working from home" /><summary type="html">Whether we want to admit it or not, everything has changed. The future of work, in light of the “new normal,” presents some very unique challenges and solutions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/woman-lying-and-typing-on-laptop-6249.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://esteemed.io/uploads/woman-lying-and-typing-on-laptop-6249.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>